

Tom Rabin

Personal Profile

I am a marketing strategist with 7 years' experience at B2B and B2C digital agencies across London, Sydney and New York. I have worked with a number of industry leading brands in technology, finance, auto and retail to deliver campaigns that create brand fame and give genuine value to the business.

I take pride in challenging my clients and am always on the look out for human insights as a means to fuel brand strategy. In a rapidly progressing industry, I am fascinated by how the functionality of digital platforms can be used in new ways to deliver content that rebukes 'conventional' advertising practice.

Experience

The Crocodile, London, Client Strategist. August 2020- Present

I'm the strategy lead across multiple accounts on the agency roster. My responsibilities include both brand and comms planning, as well as supporting clients with wider account direction. On a daily basis, I identify and solve business challenges to grow, connect and innovate accounts. On a project basis, my job is to synthesise cultural, category and competitor research into actionable insights, create propositions and build comms architectures. I work closely with the creative and content departments to guide the production process, delivering detailed briefs that help to ensure the strategic vision is maintained.

The Crocodile, London, Social Media Account Director. January 2019- July 2020

In this role, I was responsible for the strategy and execution of digital campaigns, connecting paid media to the wider marketing mix. My objectives included driving industry leading CPAs, testing media channels, and maximising ROI on behalf of leading B2B organisations. On a daily basis I would consult with client-side CMOs and CEOs to develop audience targeting based on account segmentation methods, as well as highly relevant and actionable messaging. Driving business growth within my owned accounts was a priority which has saw a revenue increase of 120% YoY.

1000heads Sydney, Account Director. January 2018- November 2018

In this position, I took a strategic account role across content creation, influencer marketing and experiential activations. My day-to-day responsibilities included dealing directly with senior clients from market leading brands to pitch campaigns and report back on performance. I was also heavily involved in new business projects, winning work to build the company roster, whilst retaining and growing the accounts within my remit. In this period my clients accounted for more than 50% of total office revenue.

1000heads Sydney, Junior Account Director. January 2017- December 2017 1000heads London, Senior Account Executive. September 2014- April 2015 1000heads London, Account Executive. December 2013- August 2014 1000heads London, Intern. September 2013- November 2013

<u>Clients</u>

Sohonet

The media & entertainment software provider wanted a campaign to promote their online collaboration tool, ClearView. I conducted an audience segmentation using psychographic and demographic data, overlaying the Five-Factor Model of Personality with Craft, Tech or Business roles to gain a deep understanding of their behaviours. The learnings helped to form the campaign proposition, Stay True to Your Vision, which appealed the motivations of all audience groups; controlling the film production workflow whilst maintaining beautiful creative output. Underpinning this, interviews uncovered the need for brand fame to build trust into new technology and a word of mouth campaign was developed using thought leadership and rich film content to change perceptions in the industry.

Royal London

Royal London tasked us with creating a campaign strategy that enabled the brand to discuss death in a way that invited pride and dignity, supporting their funeral care offering. Our "How to Die Well" positioning was born from cultural and audience insights around the changing perception of human loss, from which a comms framework and content plan were created spanning organic and media channels. We positioned Royal London as a sage-like advice-giver to their existing community and prospects, with the objective of winning market share through trust and loyalty.

Datapred

The machine learning, procurement software company requested a brand launch strategy to help them get in front of core audiences across manufacturing industries. Research into tech-adoption within raw material purchasing uncovered fears around automation replacing jobs, and an archaic approach to data gathering. Using Kahneman's theory of the decision-making systems, I looked at the tension between reactive and logical purchasing to conclude that Procurement Officers were not able to make smart decisions due to the sheer amount of data they had to manage. Through comms planning, we positioned Datapred as a partner to help audiences "get ahead", saving time to make strategic decisions and show cost savings to the C-Suite.

Verizon Media

Reporting to the Head of Marketing in EMEA, I created a content strategy for Verizon Media's UK and French social presences. This involved creating comms pillars, planning around key moments in the B2B calendar and leveraging media tactics, such as geo-targeted ads, to support offline activations. Of the several campaigns we activated, our most successful was promoting Verizon Media's activity at DMEXCO, where we captured activity in real-time and executed ads to drive foot-traffic towards the sales team.

Samsung

As client lead, I was responsible for planning and launching Samsung AU's first ever advocacy programme, #ToTheMakers. Our task was to build a vibrant community, passionate about fitness, tech and photography. My team engaged over 200 influential Samsung users, rewarding advocacy with the latest devices, exclusive experiences and Australia wide events. From our efforts, we generated more than 10,000 product recommendations online and offline, and increased mentions of "love" by 28% in association with Samsung. As part of this project, I worked closely with our Content Director to produce the world's first 360 video powered by influencers, shot using Samsung technology and showcased at live events via VR devices.

Other clients I have worked with include Google, PlayStation, PokerStars, Lebara, Isuzu and Microsoft

Skillset

Key areas of expertise include:

- -Brand strategy
- -Comms planning
- -Researching
- -Media and channel strategy
- -Client management and relationships
- -Content planning
- -Influencer strategy
- -Copywriting
- -Insights and reporting

Education

English BA Hons. 2:1. Hull University IB Diploma. Dartford Grammar School

Interests

I have been producing music for the past 12 years and have performed live all over the UK. Highlights include playing amongst Calvin Harris and Ed Sheeran at various music festivals. I also specialised in Creative Writing whilst studying English at university which led to a passion for music journalism. I have written columns in fashion publications such as 'Phoenix' and 'The Manual', as well as various online blogs.